Itachi's Story - Light and Darkness:
The Darkness of the Akatsuki
(十蔵)マイト・ダイっていう
忍を知ってるか？
Do you know a shinobi
named Might Dai?
(イタチ)マイト・ガイなら知っているが。
I know a Might Guy.
あぁ… そりゃ
あんときのガキのほうだな。
Huh, well that’s the kid from that time.
俺は 霧隠れ忍刀七人衆の
１人だったが→
I was one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist.
マイト・ダイのおかげで→
Thanks to Might Dai,
the seven of us got cut down to three.
あんときの七人衆は
三人衆にされちまったんだよ。
あんな むさ髭野郎が
あんな体術を使うなんて→
Who could have expected that
scuzzy bearded jerk
would use taijutsu like that?
誰が思うかよ。
Anyway, I wanna make
something clear...
だから はっきりしておかなきゃ
ならねえことがある。
お前が なんで
暁に入ったかなんてのは→
I could care less why
you joined the Akatsuki.
どうでもいいことだ。
別に聞きたくもない。
I don’t even want
to hear your reason.
俺が なんで暁に入ったなんてのも
どうでもいいことだ。
It doesn’t matter why I joined either.
聞きたくなければ それでもいい。
And it’s okay if
you don’t want to know.
Listen to me!
(十蔵)聞けよ！
There’s something
I need to ask you.
いいか？ お前に聞いておかなきゃ
ならないことがある。
And…
それは お前の得意忍術だ。
It’s about your ninjutsu specialties.
As you see, I use this Executioner’s Blade
and cut up enemies.
見てのとおり
俺は この首切り包丁で→
敵に切り込んでいく。
で お前は？
So? How about you?
Genjutsu, Fire Style and Shuriken Jutsu.
(イタチ)幻術 火遁 手裏剣術。
ずいぶんと控えめな野郎だな。
You’re awfully humble!
元木ノ葉の暗部 うちはイタチ。
Former ANBU Itachi Uchiha, Itachi of
the Sharingan, the Clan-Killer Itachi...
写輪眼のイタチ 一族殺しのイタチの名は
あっちこっちに響いてるぜ。
People throw around many nicknames
for you...you’re notorious.
俺らのフォーメーションを決めておく。
Let’s decide on our formations.
You’ll start with a preemptive attack
まず お前が幻術でも手裏剣でも
なんでもいいから→
with your genjutsu, shuriken or
whatever’s your specialty.
得意の術で先制攻撃をしろ。
そして 俺が突っ込む。
Then I’ll jump in.
お前は 後方から援護に入る。
And you back me up.
それが フォーメーションＢ。
That will be Formation B
(イタチ)Ａは？
What’s A?
We each do things our own way.
別々に好きにやる… だ。
了解した。
Understood.
ひとつ忠告しておくぜ。
One word of warning.
相手を
見た目で 甘く見るんじゃねえぞ。
Don’t take any opponent for granted.
了解。
Understood.
なにヤツ！
そこをどけ！
- Who are you?
- Get out of our way!
忍の里は平和だ安定だ
なんて言いながら→
Shinobi villages only say things
about peace and order,
but they’re really worried
about their roles shrinking.
その役割が小さくなることを
心配する。
水面下では
どこも相手の勢力を削ぎ→
Behind the scenes,
they’re all trying
to lessen their opponent’s power
while increasing their own.
自分の勢力を増やそうと考える。
ただし その軍事行動が
他国にバレないようにだ。
All the while, preventing other nations
from finding out their schemes.
だから 暁に仕事が来る。
That’s why the Akatsuki gets jobs.
The more peaceful the world is,
the more work we get...
世の中が平和なら平和なほどな。
We accept every request.
We don’t care about the details.
依頼があれば 何でも受ける。
内容なんか知ったこっちゃねえ。
おのれ 曲者！
You scoundrels!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
火遁 豪火球の術！
ぐあっ！
わ～！
この！
Why you—!
だから
駕籠の中身が誰かも知らない。
That’s why…
We don’t know who’s inside
this palanquin…
知る必要もない。
And we don’t want to know either.
There’s also no need to think about
だから こんな嫌がらせみたいな
仕事でも→
who the hell would pay us
to do such dirty work.
誰が何のために
依頼してきたかなんて→
考える必要もない。
That’s what the Akatsuki is about.
それが 暁だ。
リーダーのペインは→
Pain, the leader, said the Akatsuki
was going to rule the world.
暁が世界を支配すると
言っていたが。
そりゃ まだまだ先の話だ。
That won’t be for a long time.
まず 金と力を蓄えるんだとよ。
We first need to amass money
and power.
言ってるそばから お呼びだ。
Speak of the devil,
he’s summoning us.
(大蛇丸)どう イタチ君
暁には慣れた？
So Itachi, have you gotten
used to the Akatsuki?
なんなら パートナーを
替えてもらうのは どう？
How would you feel about changing
partners and teaming up with me?
私と ツーマンセルというのは？
(十蔵)おいおい ようやく
フォーメーションが固まってきたんだ。
Hey, we’re just getting
our formation down.
引き抜きは なしだぜ。
Don’t try to steal him.
(ヒルコ)パートナーを替えるっていうのは
俺も賛成だ。
I second changing partners...
相性ってもんがある。
There’s an aspect called compatibility...
リーダーも もう少し
考えてほしいところね。
I wish our leader would put
a bit more thought into this.
(ヒルコ)お前が言うな 蛇野郎！ チッ！
You’re one to talk, you damn snake!
(ペイン)お前たちの働きによって
暁の名も裏世界で広まってきた。
Thanks to your work, Akatsuki’s reputation
is growing in the underworld.
依頼される仕事の
規模も大きくなり→
The jobs we’re getting are
becoming bigger in scale,
それに見合った
報酬も手にできる。
which means higher compensation
as well.
だが それは手段に過ぎない。
暁は次の段階に入る。
But that’s only just a step.
And the Akatsuki is ready to
move on to the next step…
次は尾獣だ。
which are the Tailed Beasts.
(十蔵)尾獣って
９匹いるっていう あれか？
There’re supposed to be nine of ‘em.
Are those the Tailed Beasts?
(ペイン)その多くは
忍五大国が抱えているが→
The Five Great Ninja Nations
harbor most of them.
どこにいるのか
判明していない尾獣がいる。
But the whereabouts are unknown
for a few of them.
手の空いた者は
その所在を調査しろ。
Those who aren’t on a job
will try to locate them.
(角都)調査だけでいいのか？
(ペイン)今は まだな。
So we just have to locate them?
For now.
(大蛇丸)ゆくゆくは どうするの？
What will you do with them eventually?
(ペイン)尾獣すべてを狩り集める。
(大蛇丸)それで？
We’ll hunt down and collect
every Tailed Beast.
And then?
それが 世界征服のための
抑止力となる。
They’ll act as our deterrents in our quest
for world domination.
(大蛇丸)尾獣ねぇ 他の手段が
いくらでもあると思うけど。
Tailed Beasts?
Seems to me there are
lots of other ways…
(ゼツ)リーダーの考えに間違いはない。
There’s no mistake in
the leader’s reasoning.
任務を割り振る。
Here are the assignments.
十蔵 お前たちは
水の国からの依頼だ。
Juzo…
You’ll handle the request
from the Land of Water.
ウヘッ 別の任務は ねえのかよ？
Isn’t there another mission I can do?!
(ペイン)お前なら
土地勘があるだろう。
You’re familiar with the territory.
(十蔵)チッ！
ムチャ振りしやがる。
This is ridiculous.
あんな辛気臭ぇとこ 二度と
行きたくなかったんだがな。
I never wanted to go back
to that depressing place.
(イタチ)アンタの元里か。
Is that the village where you’re from?
(十蔵)仕事としては単純だ。
The job’s easy.
水の国の大名家の
とある人物を暗殺する。
We have to assassinate a member
from the Feudal Lord's clan
in the Land of Water.
解説してやるが→
I'll explain...
これは 水の国でよくある
お家騒動 お跡目争いだ。
It’s an intra-clan fight
over succession,
a common occurrence in
the Land of Water.
大名家に対して
霧隠れの里は介入できない。
The Hidden Mist cannot interfere
in the Feudal Clan's affairs.
だから 暁に依頼が来た。
That’s why they’ve come to the Akatsuki.
(十蔵)この河が国境だが
水の国に来たことはあるか？
This river’s the border.
Have you ever been to
the Land of Water?
(イタチ)任務ではない。
Never on a mission.
遠足か？
So for an outing then?
ノリの悪い野郎だな。
You’ve got no sense of humor!
だが 水の国の領地で→
But you do know, don’t you?
What happens to a shinobi
from another village
他里の忍が発見されたら
どうなるかは知ってるな？
if he’s discovered in
the Land of Water?
霧隠れは捕虜交換に応じない。
The Hidden Mist doesn’t have
a policy for prisoner exchange...
捕まった忍は その術を→
If captured, the shinobi will be made
to divulge his jutsu
徹底的に暴かれたうえに消される。
and he’ll be disposed of.
お前は まだいいぜ イタチ。
You have it good, Itachi.
木ノ葉は ぬるい。
The Leaf is naïve.
お前や大蛇丸が のうのうと
抜け忍やってられるんだからな。
That’s why you and Orochimaru can go
around without a care as Rogue Ninja...
霧隠れには 追い忍っていう
抜け忍狩り専門の部隊がある。
There is a special unit in the Hidden Mist
that track down Rogue Ninja.
俺が この里で捕らえられたら…。
If I ever get caught in this village…
あ～ フォーメーションＣを忘れてたぜ。
Oh, I forgot all about Formation C.
もし俺が霧隠れに捕まったら
お前の手で さっさと殺してくれ。
If I’m caught by the Mist,
kill me immediately.
余裕があれば。
If I have a chance.
フォーメーションＤのときは
どうしてほしい？
So what do you want me
to do for Formation D?
特に希望はない。
Nothing in particular.
んじゃ 行くか。
Fine, let’s get going!
お前 忍び込むってのは
うまいほうか？
Are you good at infiltrating?
普通だ。
んじゃ それを見せてもらおうか。
I'm average.
Okay, show me.
た 頼む 命だけは…。
P-Please! Spare me!
(十蔵)
アンタに恨みがあるわけじゃない。
I don’t bear a grudge against you.
ただ 仕事なんでな。
This is just my job.
ま 待ってくれ！
W-Wait!
おい。
あぁ。
Hey…
Yeah.
霧隠れの術。
Hidden Mist Jutsu…!
(やぐら)風遁 台風一過！
Wind Style! Supreme Typhoon!
こいつは…。
This is—?!
四代目。
Lord Fourth!
水影か。
俺の忠告を覚えてるか？
Is that the Mizukage?
Do you remember my warning?
(イタチ)どう見ても子供だな。
Any way you look at him,
he’s a kid.
あれで 三尾の人柱力だ。
He’s the Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails.
んで これが霧隠れの追い忍。
And they are the Mist’s
Shinobi Tracking Unit.
(やぐら)まさか お前がこの里に→
I never expected you to reappear
in the Village, Juzo.
再び現れるとは思わなかったぞ
十蔵。
俺だって来たかなかったんだが
しようがねえ。
I didn’t wanna come back either.
I had no choice.
お前に言いたいことは
海ほどあるが→
I have a ton of things to say to you…
少なくとも その首切り包丁は
里に返してもらう。
At the very least, I’m taking back
the Executioner’s Blade.
お前のその仲間が
写輪眼のイタチであろうともな。
Even if your partner
is Itachi of the Sharingan.
あ～ となると不意打ちで
お前の幻術ってわけにも→
So I guess a surprise attack with
your genjutsu is meaningless.
ちょっと いかねえな。
どうする？
What do you want to do?
フォーメーションＣだな こりゃ。
This one’s a Formation C.
フォーメーションＣか 了解した。
Formation C? Understood.
見るな！
Don’t look!
水分身!?
It's a Water Clone!
(十蔵)イタチ！
火遁 豪火球の術！
Itachi!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu.
あっ！
四代目！
Lord Fourth!
ヘッ。
お前たち 容赦しないぞ！
You two…
I’ll show no mercy.
尾獣化!?
Tailed Beast State?!
The Fourth is a Jinchuriki
who can control his Tailed Beast!
四代目は 尾獣のコントロールができる
人柱力だ。
This is not the Hidden Leaf!
木ノ葉と一緒にすんじゃねえぞ！
Juzo!
十蔵！
四代目の珊瑚掌の術だ！
It’s the Fourth’s Coral Palm Jutsu.
うお～！
Juzo?!
十蔵！
ぐほ…。
Run… Itachi…
逃げろ イタチ…。
W-What?!
なんだ？
これは…。
What is this?
あぁ うあ～!!
The power of the Mangekyo Sharingan?
万華鏡写輪眼の力!?
うっ…。
Why you—!
こっ この…。
十蔵。
Juzo…?
水影を やったのか？
Did you kill…the Mizukage?
いや まだ死んだわけじゃない。
No, he’s not dead yet.
じゃあ… ゴフッ！ 早く行け。
しかし…。
Then…
Hurry! Go!
But…
俺が もうダメだってのは→
It's all over for me…
医療班でもない お前にだって
わかるだろうが。
You don’t have to be
a Medic Ninja to know that, right?
(イタチ)すまない。
バカ言うな。
I’m sorry.
What a stupid thing to say.
誰かに何か伝えたいことがあれば
聞いておく。
Do you have any last words
for anyone?
ハッ バカ野郎。
Like I'd have anyone, idiot.
そんなヤツ 誰もいねえよ。
(十蔵)そうか。 お前には
そういうヤツが いるんだな。
I see…But you have someone
like that, huh?
さっさと行け。
Hurry and go!
俺は ただ この元いた場所で
くたばるだけだ。
I’m just gonna drop dead, right here,
where I'm from…
…this god-forsaken,
Blood Mist Village…
(十蔵)この忌々しい血霧の里で。
俺の相棒は
こいつだけだと思っていたが…。
I thought my only partner…
was this guy here, but…
(ペイン)枇杷十蔵が やられた。
Juzo Biwa is dead.
(大蛇丸)おや まあ
イタチ君と一緒だったというのに。
Oh my, and he was
your teammate, Itachi.
(イタチ)相手は 三尾の人柱力だった。
The Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails killed him.
(大蛇丸)では イタチ君は 水影相手に
無事 戻ってきたってことね。
Which means you took on
the Mizukage and came out of it alive.
(ペイン)やられたのは もう１人いる。
Another one of us is dead.
Rather than being killed by the enemy,
he was killed by friendly fire.
(ゼツ)敵に やられたというよりは→
味方に やられたというところだ。
(角都)
あの野郎が グズグズしてただけだ。
He was just too slow.
(ゼツ)その判断は 皆に任せる。
Let everyone here be the judge of that.
(角都)火遁 頭刻苦！
Fire Style: Searing Migraine!
(ヒルコ)故意だな。
(大蛇丸)わざとね。
Done in bad faith.
Sounds like it was on purpose.
He should have just dodged it.
(角都)かわせばいいだけの話だ。
You ignored your partner, didn't you?
(大蛇丸)あなた 相棒をずいぶんと
疎んじてたでしょ。
So what?
それが なんだ？
殺したいと思ってたんじゃない？
You wanted to kill him, didn't you?
それが なんだ？
いいえ よくあることだから。
So what?
Oh, nothing. It just seems
to happen a lot.
(ペイン)暁は ツーマンセルで動く
どうする？ 角都。
The Akatsuki works in two-man teams.
What will you do, Kakuzu?
相棒を失った者同士
イタチと組むか？
Will you team up with Itachi
who’s also lost his partner?
As long as he doesn’t irritate me.
(角都)コイツが 俺を
イラつかせなきゃ それでいい。
(イタチ)俺は アンタの
ご機嫌の取り方を知らない。
I wouldn’t know how to cater
to your moods.
なんだとテメエ
じゃあ 組んで教えてやろう。
What the hell did you say?
Then let's team up and I'll show you.
(大蛇丸)待って。
イタチ君とは 私が組むわ。
Wait, I’ll team up with Itachi.
Are you trying to make a fool out of me?!
(ヒルコ)テメエ 俺をコケにする気か。
(ペイン)暁には 新しいメンバーが必要だ。
The Akatsuki needs to
find some new members.
そのときまで
この件は保留にする。
We’ll put this issue on hold until we do.
うっ…。
(大蛇丸)永遠の命って
何かわかる？ イタチ君。
Do you know what eternal life is, Itachi?
うっ…。
私にも まだわからない。
だから 新しい肉体がいるの。
I don’t know yet, either.
That’s why I need a new body.
永遠に連なる すばらしい肉体が。
A magnificent body to link me
to eternal life.
それは しょせん
お前の欲の問題だ。
First of all, the problem with you…
is your greed.
まさか この私が金縛りの術に…。
Impossible! Have I fallen prey to
the Paralysis Jutsu?
なんという瞳力 すばらしい…。
What incredible Visual Prowess…
Magnificent!
うっ うぅ…。
大蛇丸… お前のいかなる術も→
Orochimaru…
Try all of the jutsu you wish...
この眼の前では
何の効力も持たない。
But, my eyes can see through
all of them.
言ってくれるじゃないの。
You're so blunt…
I’m not sure what to do with you.
俺は アンタを どうすればいいのか
わからない。
ここで このまま殺せばいいのか。
あるいは 何か使い道があるのか。
Whether to kill you right now,
or find a way to use you.
イタチ…。
I-Itachi!
お前には足りないのだ。
You just don’t have enough...
いや 足り過ぎている。 欲望が。
No, you lack it completely...the greed…
お前は 人の命を…。
for human life!
Lord Orochimaru!
(カブト)大蛇丸様！
I’ll definitely get you back for this.
(大蛇丸)この借りは
返すわよ 必ず。
(ペイン)大蛇丸が
組織を裏切り 抜けていった。
Orochimaru betrayed and
deserted our organization.
(ヒルコ)けっ！
あの野郎 やっぱりか。
I knew it, that bastard.
組織よりも
自分のことを優先しやがった。
He always put himself
before the organization.
(ペイン)大蛇丸を このままに
しておくつもりはないが→
I don’t intend to let Orochimaru
get away with this,
今は メンバーが足りない。
but right now,
we’re short members.
(トビ)はい！ はい！ はい！
僕を入れては どうでしょう？
Hey! Hey! Hey!
How about letting me join?
(ヒルコ)すっこんでろ。
(トビ)はい…。
Get lost!
Okay…
大蛇丸のことは 俺に任せな。
Leave Orochimaru to me.
ヤツが 部下に使っている
カブトってのは→
His subordinate, Kabuto, is my puppet.
俺の傀儡人形みたいなもんだ。
すぐに隠れ場所をつかんでやる。
I’ll find out where
he’s hiding out in no time.
(ペイン)そう急ぐな。
お前の相棒の目星はつけている。
No need to rush.
I have someone in mind
to be your partner.
ソイツを仲間に引き入れてからだ。
It can wait until he joins us.
(角都)俺は どうする？
イタチと組むのか？
What about me?
Do I team up with Itachi?
もう少し １人でいろ。
Work alone for a while longer.
イタチには 別の相棒を用意してる。
I have someone else I’ve prepared
to partner up with Itachi.
(鬼鮫)今日から あなたと
組むことになった者です。
I’m going to be your partner
from today.
Hey, you over there!
I’m not gonna fall for
your genjutsu ever again, hmm!
I’m going to give you a little taste
of what art is.
Let's leave it at that.
Sasori…
partner with Deidara and
go kill Orochimaru.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Par